[
  {
    "question": "KAIZEN IS DERIVED FROM HOW MANY ROOT WORDS",
    "answer": "2 - Kai and Zen",
    "difficulty": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "MUDA MEANS",
    "answer": "Waste",
    "difficulty": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "KAIZEN ORIGINATED IN WHAT COUNTRY",
    "answer": "Japan",
    "difficulty": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "S.M.E.D IS AN ACRONYM FOR:",
    "answer": "Single Minute Exchange of Die",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "KAIZEN FOUNDATION FOCUSES ON 5 MAIN PRINCIPLES. THE FIRST PRINCIPLE IS:",
    "answer": "Create Customer Value",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Do not make Errors, Do not Transfer Errors, Notify when an error about to occur  and standardize are all subsets of",
    "answer": "Auto Quality",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "The KAIZEN flag has three colors: red, white and blue. Blue Stands for?",
    "answer": "Standardization",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "A model, a rule, or a habit that influences the way we interpret a given situation or problem is called",
    "answer": "Paradigm",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the main standard characteristics?",
    "answer": "Clear, simple, unique, visual and accessible",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "What is processing time?",
    "answer": "The time it takes flow unit to pass through the process, from beginning to end",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "A standardized routine that involves committing senior employees to solve a problem when it arises, and then escalating it if it's needed is called",
    "answer": "A Help Chain",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "Visual Management System which uses cards to reinforce work habits and perform audits is called:",
    "answer": "Audit Kamishibai",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "The tool used in Monitoring on a monthly basis Each Improvement Priority and its Targets To Improve on the X-matrix is called",
    "answer": "The Bowling chart",
    "difficulty": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "Standards are the best ways we know today of doing a process. Name 3 main types of standard?",
    "answer": "Execution Standards, Inspection Standards, One Point Lesson, Checklist",
    "difficulty": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "In continuous improvement, storage area that has an easy picking access, using visual management and in which the replenishment is triggered by consumption is called a:",
    "answer": "Supermarket",
    "difficulty": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "Kaizen Means",
    "answer": "Change for better/Continuous Improvement",
    "difficulty": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "GEMBA means",
    "answer": "Where the value is added/Shop Floor.",
    "difficulty": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "MURI means",
    "answer": "Overburdening",
    "difficulty": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "MURA means",
    "answer": "Uneveness",
    "difficulty": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "KAIZEN was first associated with what company.",
    "answer": "Toyota",
    "difficulty": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "THE FATHER OF KAIZEN IS",
    "answer": "Maasaki Imai",
    "difficulty": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "ANYTHING A CUSTOMER IS WILLING TO PAY FOR IS CALLED:",
    "answer": "VALUE",
    "difficulty": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "POKE YOKE IS ASSOCIATED WITH",
    "answer": "ERROR-PROOFING",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "AN EASY ACRONYM FOR OPERATIONAL WASTE IS",
    "answer": "TIMWOOD(S)",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "N.V.A AND V.A ARE ACROYNMS FOR?",
    "answer": "NON VALUE ADDED AND VALUE ADDED",
    "difficulty": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "IN THE KAIZEN WAY, WE AIM FOR:",
    "answer": "TRUE NORTH",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "The top management should be engaged in the process of change...",
    "answer": "All the time",
    "difficulty": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "Do not make Errors, Do not Transfer Errors, Notify when an error is about to occur  and standardize are all subsets of",
    "answer": "Auto Quality",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "The KAIZEN?�? flag has three colors: red, white and blue. Red Stands for?",
    "answer": "Innovation",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "He/She helps WS Sponsor & Initiative Lead to define value upfront and Follows value through L-Gates to bank",
    "answer": "Value Analysts",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "The KAIZEN?�? flag has three colors: red, white and blue. White Stands for?",
    "answer": "Improvement",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "Daily Kaizen has 4 levels. The Level 1 DK is also called",
    "answer": "Team Organization",
    "difficulty": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "In Daily Kaizen, teams that perform similar work and have the same goals from top management to shop floor operators are called",
    "answer": "Natural teams",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Daily Kaizen Level meeting are typically short standup meetings. The average duration of each Daily Kaizen meeting is:",
    "answer": "15 minutes",
    "difficulty": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "A DK Level consists of how many core components",
    "answer": "4",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "VMB stands for",
    "answer": "Visual Management Board",
    "difficulty": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "The purpose of 5s is to Organize the work area in order to improve the visual management and increase efficiency. The first S stands for:",
    "answer": "Sort",
    "difficulty": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "Name 2 basic continuous improvement tools? (Any 2 will be correct)",
    "answer": "5S, visual management, Standard work, 3C, PDCA",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Mention the 5s",
    "answer": "Sort, straighten, scrub, standardize, sustain",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "What does DK L4 focus on",
    "answer": "Advanced problem solving",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "What is one of the biggest challenge to implementing Kaizen?",
    "answer": "Breaking paradigms",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the main standard characteristics?",
    "answer": "Clear, simple, unique, visual, accessible",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "The easiest, simplest and safest way of doing the work known so far is called",
    "answer": "A standard",
    "difficulty": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "Which teams should perform daily kaizen?",
    "answer": "All natural teams",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main goal of implementing SMED?",
    "answer": "Reduction of total loss time due to setup/ Reduce  Machine set up time.",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "What are Gemba Walks' goals?",
    "answer": "Confirm the process and engage the people on the shopfloor",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "What do you need to do to change the culture of a company?",
    "answer": "Transform the Gemba and the behaviors of the people",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "In the CI change process, who changes first? The Gemba or the people",
    "answer": "The Gemba",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "How many levels of Self-Quality/Auto Quality are there?",
    "answer": "2",
    "difficulty": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "The 5 Kaizen Principles focus on different habits and behaviors which we must imbibe to improve workplace and people satisfaction. The 2nd Principle ?�� ?��Create Flow efficiency?�� seeks to:",
    "answer": "Minimise and Eliminate the 7 wastes in Operations",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "A process to transform the Organization's Mission in 3-5 years goals and on annual winning priorities is called",
    "answer": "Hoshin Planning/Strat Kaizen/X-matrix Deployment",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "The tool used in Monitoring on a monthly basis Each Improvement Priority and its Targets To Improve on the X-matrix is called",
    "answer": "A bowling chart",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "A one page strategy document that summarises 3-5 Years goals, annual targets, breakthrough initiatives and targets to improve and the responsible Business Unit is called",
    "answer": "The X-matrix",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "Standards are the best ways we know today of doing a process. Name 3 main types of standard?",
    "answer": "Execution Standards, Inspection Standards, One Point Lesson, Checklist",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "Standard work is developed in 5 steps. What are the first and the Last steps.",
    "answer": "1. Definition of SMART goals 5. consolidation",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "In NLNG,?� Workstreams are the powerhouse for driving initiatives. How many workstreams are in NLNG",
    "answer": "7",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "In work Environment can the 5S be implemented",
    "answer": "Physically, Virtually or transactionally",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "The difference because the current situation and the Expected state is called",
    "answer": "A problem",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "Examples of a Question that Visual Management can help to answer?",
    "answer": "What are the goals of the team and are they being met.",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "External Work and internal work refer to classification under what CI Methodology",
    "answer": "SMED",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "In continuous improvement, storage area that has an easy picking access, using visual management and in which the replenishment is triggered by consumption is called a:",
    "answer": "A supermarket",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the two different ways of store supermarket references?",
    "answer": "Flow racks and/or containers on wheels (Trolleys)",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "A methodology to observe and simplify/improve a certain task is called",
    "answer": "Standard Work",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "The calculations ?��Production Time Available (without stoppages) / Client Demand (on that period of time)?�� is used to determine",
    "answer": "Takt Time",
    "difficulty": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "What does de acronym OEE means?",
    "answer": "Overall Equipment Efficiency",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "OEE is calculated as",
    "answer": "Availability x Quality x Performance",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "What methodology is used in Kobetsu?",
    "answer": "A3 Thinking",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "In which step of Kobetsu is the Ishikawa diagram used?",
    "answer": "Step 4",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the three divisions of a A3 9 steps?",
    "answer": "Preparation (steps 1 to 3), Solution Design (steps 4 to 6) and Implementation of a Tracking System (steps 7 to 9)",
    "difficulty": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the first step to implement a Poke Yoke system?",
    "answer": "Detect the failures in their point of origin",
    "difficulty": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the Key component of an A3 step 9 is (Any one of the listed responses",
    "answer": "1. Develop SOP, or 2.Train users in the new improvement, or  3. Document and share lessons learnt",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is it important to implement a iObeya Room?",
    "answer": "TO visually track the progress of all projects",
    "difficulty": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of investment does a Poke Yoke system usually implies?",
    "answer": "Poke Yoke systems are usually low-cost solutions",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "What is an Ishikawa diagram used for?",
    "answer": "To categorize the potential causes of a problem",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "What means flow efficiency?",
    "answer": "Sum of all V.A activities compared with the process time",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "What is processing time?",
    "answer": "The time that the flow unit takes to pass through the process, from beginning to end",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the aim of resource efficiency?",
    "answer": "Maximise the time spent adding value",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "When discussing Resource Efficiency, the acronym OPE refers to:",
    "answer": "Overall People Efficiency",
    "difficulty": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "Variability Losses are reduced by the implementation of",
    "answer": "Resource Efficiency Methodology",
    "difficulty": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the critical chain?",
    "answer": "It is the path that determines the project duration",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main goal of Daily Kaizen?",
    "answer": "Minimise the variability of results, and contribute to the creation of a Continuous Improvement Culture",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "Name 2 tools that can be used in Strat Review",
    "answer": "Market Study, Voice of Customer VOC, Value Stream Analysis, WWLL (what Winner Looks Like)",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "How do we find the cause of a problem?",
    "answer": "Look for causes in Gemba, use the 5 Whys method or an Ishikawa Diagram.",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "How can you implement the 5th S (sustain)?",
    "answer": "By Improving the standards and do audits",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "The later a defect is detected in the value chain:",
    "answer": "The greater the non-quality cost associated",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "Definition of SMART goals, study the actual situation, implementation of improvement ideas, work standardisation, consolidation are processes associated with",
    "answer": "Standard work",
    "difficulty": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "1. Define the Objective 2. Study of the task 3. Design of the solution 4. Standardization 5. Training and Consolidation are steps in what CI tool",
    "answer": "Standard Work",
    "difficulty": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "Improve productivity, improve service level, reduce stock, reduce the occupied area, decrease waste and variability are the main goals of a",
    "answer": "Border of Line",
    "difficulty": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "Define external and internal work",
    "answer": "External Work- Tasks that can be performed while the machine is running and  Internal Work: Tasks that can only be performed when the machine is not running",
    "difficulty": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "What we need to show in closing A3?",
    "answer": "Initiative, initial situation, final situation, Results",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "1. Study of the work 2.Separation of internal and external work 3. Conversion of internal to external work 4. Reduction of internal work 5. Reduction of external work are the key steps in what CI methodology",
    "answer": "SMED",
    "difficulty": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "List the 5 Kaizen Principles",
    "answer": "1- Create value for the client; 2- Create flux efficiency; 3- Be gemba oriented; 4- Train People; 5- Speak with data.",
    "difficulty": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "You cannot solve a problem with the same thinking that created them is a statement associated with",
    "answer": "Paradigm",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "Case, Cause and Countermeasures are terms associated with the 3C. What kind of tool is the 3C",
    "answer": "Problem solving tool",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "Because 83% of the information that the human being perceive is acquired through vision. So, it is essential that all relevant information should be exposed in a visual manner. This is a key justification given for:",
    "answer": "Visual management",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "A flash card carrying all the information about the status of your work and the work required to be done is called",
    "answer": "A kanban",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "True or False: Visualize the task you working on and the items in context of each other is a principle of which Kanban works on.",
    "answer": "TRUE",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "In a Production line with more than one machine, where the OEE should be measured?",
    "answer": "On the last machine of the line (As there may be non-compliant product by the end of the line, the OEE should be measured at the end)",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "Process selection, Current Stata Analysis, Opportunities Identification, Future State Design, Implementation are all steps in:",
    "answer": "Process Optimisation/Process Map/Value Stream Mapping",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "The Value Stream KAIZEN?�? cycle lasts for howmany years",
    "answer": "1 year",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "KAIZEN?�? Events are a standard format to carry out and close any KAIZEN?�? implementation. What is the objective of this methodology?",
    "answer": "To ensure a successful execution of disruptive improvements in organisations",
    "difficulty": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the fundamental principle of auto-quality?",
    "answer": "The next process is your customer",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "Border of line is the interface between:",
    "answer": "Production and internal logistics",
    "difficulty": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "Create flow in Internal Logistics, Minimize muda activities by the operators, Reduce shortage of parts in the production line are all advantages of implementing the",
    "answer": "Mizusumashi/Water spider",
    "difficulty": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "True or False? Gemba observation is a not fundamental step towards understanding real everyday problems.",
    "answer": "FALSE",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "In TPM, there are how many types of losses.",
    "answer": "16 different types",
    "difficulty": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "The TPM model groups losses into losses of",
    "answer": "performance, availability and quality",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Establish the relationship between the detection point and the point of origin of defects using what tool",
    "answer": "Auto-Quality Tools",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "Name 4 ways KAIZEN?�? improves any operation",
    "answer": "Safety, Quality, Cost, Delivery, Motivation and Growth/Innovation (SQCDMG)",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "X-matrix is a 3 ?�� 5 years planning tool with a 1-year implementation target. Which of the W is not represented on the quadrants of the X-Matrix?",
    "answer": "When",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "The Kaizen principle which focuses on Developing leaders, defining and agreeing with the operator clear objectives and timelines, coaching, empowerment and support is principle number",
    "answer": "4",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "Reorder the step for Muda Elimination:\n1. Eliminate what customers are not willing to pay (Muda),\n2. Identify value-added and non-value-added activities.\n3. Reinforce value-added activities.",
    "answer": "2-1-3",
    "difficulty": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the senses is the most powerfull one?�in the process of gathering data?",
    "answer": "Eye",
    "difficulty": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "What should a work instruction have?",
    "answer": "Symbol,shape and colours legend that are on the equipment,  the task list and the material for each task (include photos, if possible)",
    "difficulty": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a Poke Yoke?",
    "answer": "It is a system that?�avoids the production or?�transmission of an error/defect",
    "difficulty": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the A3 9 steps method?",
    "answer": "Is a framework to simplfy, organise and plan problem solving projects",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "Phase-Gate Design, Project Initiation, Planning Optimization, Obeya Control and Portfolio Management are the 5 Steps of",
    "answer": "Lean Project Management (LPM)",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of losses are reduced/eliminated with Flow Efficiency implementation?",
    "answer": "Process Waste Losses",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "Selection of project management methodology based on size and characteristics in portfolio management is called",
    "answer": "Tailoring",
    "difficulty": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "This refers to opportunities which exist but have not been fully utilized or tapped. Sometimes signifying under performance and loss of our competitive Edge. tHIS DEFINES",
    "answer": "Gap to Potential",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "The price paid for products or services that are inconsistent with the customer requirements is call",
    "answer": "Non-Quality Cost",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "What are 6 Sigma projects related to?",
    "answer": "Quality",
    "difficulty": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "SIPOC is an acronym for",
    "answer": "Supplier Input Process Output and Customer",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "True or False: The Lessons Learnt are filled in the end of each cycle, in order to improve the next cycle by avoiding the mistakes.",
    "answer": "TRUE",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the difference between the analysis on cause-and-effect in the Ishikawa Diagram and in The 5 Whys?",
    "answer": "The Ishikawa displays several causes for the same problem, while The 5 Whys accumulates iterations towards the root cause",
    "difficulty": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "The difference between traditional project management (waterfall) and agile?�project management is that...",
    "answer": "...waterfall requires all the goals to be defined before development starts",
    "difficulty": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "A bar chart with decreasing values, showing that 20% of the possible causes explain 80% of the problems is  called",
    "answer": "Pareto Charts",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the 3-quality rule",
    "answer": "We cannot improve what we cannot control -> we cannot control what we cannot measure -> we cannot measure what is not defined",
    "difficulty": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "Why apply a Process Mapping analysis?",
    "answer": "We apply Process mapping analysis to understand processes constrains and problems",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "True or False: Extensive documentation of the processes is not one of the key values of the agile manifesto?",
    "answer": "FALSE",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "True or False: A user story is a brief and simple requirement according to the perspective of the user",
    "answer": "TRUE",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "Story points are defined using...",
    "answer": "... a Fibonacci Sequence.",
    "difficulty": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "The burndown chart Measures the remaining story points of a specific project. In a burndown chart the real rate should be...",
    "answer": "... coincident with?�desire rate.",
    "difficulty": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "Where do you implement a project buffer",
    "answer": "At the end of a critical chain",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "Six SIgma",
    "answer": "A customer-focused problem-solving methodology that uses powerful statistical tools to reduce variation and improve processes.",
    "difficulty": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "any resource during the Process, which is not recognized by the Customer as increasing the value they receive",
    "answer": "Waste",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "The NLNG CI landscape is made up 4 parts. Daily Kaizen, Kaizen Event, WS Cadence and DRB Cadence. The part which is best suited for when a problem requires a quick fix is",
    "answer": "Kaizen Event",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "Weekly cadence of a specialized/focus business unit typically with more players and more heterogenous teams best describes which part of the NLNG CI Lanscape",
    "answer": "WS cadence",
    "difficulty": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "Define a project",
    "answer": "An improvement action whose size and scope are big and usually span longer periods than 6 months. Projects will typically require significant change from the existing process, product or service",
    "difficulty": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the NLNG 4 Cadence Principles",
    "answer": "VAlue, PAce, Accountability and Disciplined Delivery",
    "difficulty": 5
  },
  {
    "question": "In the cadence framework, the person responsible for Responsible for Initiative delivery from L1 - L5, tracking and banking value, update WS Visual Board Develops & regularly updates Initiative A3, and presents at WS Cadence Presents Initiative at DRB deep dive Participate in WS Health Check is called",
    "answer": "THe Initiative manager",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "True or FalseGTP can be monetary or otherwise.",
    "answer": "TRUE",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Equipment verification Check list can be developed to improve \"Coaching and training\" process?",
    "answer": "No. Coaching and training routines must be applied to develop team members and not to improve equipments",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "What does visual management mean?",
    "answer": "Visual Management means to manage, measure, control or take decisions recurring to visual aides like graphics, signs, etc.",
    "difficulty": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "Quality wall will help us to reduce quality defects. True or False?",
    "answer": "False, quality wall will help to identify the type of defects and the sources of defects. It will not solve the quality issues as a tool",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "Name two main reasons why we do a \"Spend analysis\".",
    "answer": "Sourcing Organisation and Sourcing Visibility,  To have a general overview on the high spend items in our business",
    "difficulty": 5
  }
]
